Finding Aid for a Collection of Material from the Trianon Press, ca. 1952-1983 LSC.1685
UCLA Library Special Collections
A Collection of Material from the Trianon Press
circa 1952-1983
UCLA Library Special Collections
Unknown.
LSC.1685
2 oversize_boxes
The collection consists of reproductions of engravings, etchings, and other artwork published by Trianon Press, a publishing house started by Arnold Fawcus who was well known for producing high quality facsimiles.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942328063606533
Biography/History
Trianon Press was founded in Paris in 1947 by Arnold Fawcus who became well known for producing high quality facsimile art prints. Under the label Trianon Press, he published a number of facsimiles including the work of William Blake. After Fawcus's death, his wife Julie Fawcus continued and completed Trianon's final two projects on Dante Alighieri and John Constable.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of reproductions of engravings, etchings, and other artwork. Among the artists represented are: William Blake, Pieter Brueghel the Elder, Charles-Germain de Saint-Aubin, Camille Pissaro, Fra Bartolommeo, Jean Bérain and Wenceslaus Hollar.
Trianon Press.
- Jerusalem, the Emanation of the Giant Albion, ca. 1804-1832.; Print 1 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Four prints from William Blake's epic poem.
- The World of Seven Virtues (ca. 1560) and The Gates of Paradise, (ca. 1793).; Prints 2-4 (Box 1)
  Two images from The World of Seven Virtues by Pieter Brueghel the Elder (representing Justice and Hope). Also, 5 images from The Gates of Paradise by William Blake.
- Untitled, undated., Print 5 (Box 1)
  Four landscape images and two pastoral scenes including one with caption "The Holy Mother to be draped in dark…"
- Seven Deadly Sins and The Gates of Paradise, (ca. 1558) (ca. 1793).; Prints 6-9 (Box 1)
  Selection of two images from the Seven Deadly Sins by Pieter Brueghel the Elder. Also, five images from The Gates of Paradise by William Blake.
- Essay de Papilloneries Humaines and Gates of Paradise, (ca. 1750) (ca. 1793).; Prints 10-12 (Box 1)
  Two prints from Essay de Papilloneries Humaines by Charles-Germain de Saint-Aubin and five selected prints from Gates of Paradise by William Blake.
- Essay de Papilloneries Humaines and Adoration of the Magi, (ca. 1750) (ca. 1130-1135).; Prints 13-16 (Box 1)
  Two images from Essay de Papilloneries Humaines by Charles-Germain de Saint-Aubin and two images of the Adoration of the Magi capital at Autun Cathedral sculpted by Gislebertus.
- Essay de Papilloneries Humaines and untitled sketches, (ca. 1750) (ca. 19th century).; Print 17 (Box 1)
  Two images from Essay de Papilloneries Humaines by Charles-Germain de Saint-Aubin and two images of sketches of women by John Constable.
- Temptation of Christ, ca. 1550s.; Print 18-19 (Box 1)
  Selection of landscape images by Pieter Brueghel including Temptation of Christ printed by Hiernonymous Cock.
- Blake prints, ca. 18th century.; Print 20 (Box 1)
  Selection of four images by William Blake.
- Raccolta di paesi e vedute dal vero originale di mano di Andrea del Sarto, ca. late 15th century to early 16th century.; Print 21-32 (Box 1)
  Selection of landscape drawings by Fra Bartolommeo.
- Landscape drawings, ca. 19th century.; Print 33-35 (Box 1)
  Selection of landscape drawings by Camille Pissaro.
- Twelve Large Landscapes, mid-16th century.; Prints 36-39 (Box 1)
  Selected images from a landscape series by Pieter Brueghel the Elder, includes Penitent Magdalene, Flight into Egypt.
- Recueil des modes de la cour de France and Adoration of the Magi, (ca. late 17th century) (ca. 1130-1135).; Prints 40-47 (Box 1)
  Selection of images from Recueil des modes de la cour de France by Jean Berain, ca. late 17th century. Also, includes one close-up image of the Adoration of the Magi capital by Gislebertus at Autun Cathedral.
- Recueil des modes de la cour de France, ca. 17th century.; Print 48 (Box 1)
  9 selected images of French fashions including Habit d'Hyuer, Habit d'Esté and Habit de Printemps by Jean Berain.
- Untitled sketches, ca. 19th century.; Prints 49-51 (Box 1)
  Selection of sketches by Richard Doyle, illustrator. Note: printed front and back.
- An Island in the Moon, ca. 1780s.; Prints 52-54 (Box 1)
  Selection of pages reproduced from An Island in the Moon by William Blake. Note: Printed front and back.
- The Art of Graving and Etching, , ca. 17th century.; Prints 55-56 (Box 1)
  Selection of pages and illustrations reproduced from The Art of Graving and Etching by William Faithorne. Note: one print has images on both front and back.
- Mascarades, , ca. 1597.; Prints 57-61 (Box 1)
  Each with a selection of 5 images of assorted costumes from Mascarades by Robert Bouillard.
- The Twelve Months, ca. 17th century.; Print 62-67 (Box 1)
  Each with a selection of 2 images from the series The Twelve Months by Jan van de Velde.
- Muscarum scarabeorum, ca. 1646.; Print 68 (Box 1)
  By Wenceslaus Hollar. A selection of 12 images of insects.
- Mantegna Tarocchi, artist and date unknown., Prints 1-6 (Box 2)
  48 images in total, 8 per page.
- Untitled, undated., Print 7-10 (Box 2)
  Selected images of landscapes and seascapes include seascapes by Joseph Mallord William Turner, ca. 19th century.
- Turner seascapes and Autun Cathedral capitals, (ca. 19th century) (ca. 1130-1135).; Print 11-13 (Box 2)
  Selection of seascapes by Joseph Mallord William Turner. Also Flight into Egypt and Adoration of the Magi, capitals carved by Gislebertus at Autun Cathedral.
- Balli di Sfessania and Varie Figure Gobbi, (ca. 1622) (ca. 1616).; Print 14-15 (Box 2)
  Selection of images from Balli di Sfessania by Jacques Callot and Varie Figure Gobbi by Jacques Callot.
- Balli di Sfessania, (ca. 1622).; Print 16 (Box 2)
  Selection of images from Balli di Sfessania by Jacques Callot.
- Untitled, mid-16th century.; Print 17 (Box 2)
  Trio of portraits of French court members by School of Clouet. Marquis de Guise and Gaspard II de Coligny by François Clouet, Marguerite de Valois, Queen of Navarre by Jean Clouet.
- Untitled, mid-16th century.; Print 18 (Box 2)
  Trio of portraits of French court members by School of Clouet. Count of Brissac by François Clouet, Antoine de Bourbon King of Navarre by Studio of Clouet, Dona Beatrix Pacheo by Jean Clouet.
- Untitled, mid-16th century.; Print 19 (Box 2)
  Trio of portraits of French court members by the School of Clouet. Includes Anne de Montmorency by François Clouet and Gaspard II de Coligny by François Clouet.
- Untitled, mid-16th century.; Print 19-20 (Box 2)
  2 prints of a trio of portraits of French court members by School of Clouet. Marguerite de Valois, Queen of Navarre by François Clouet, Louis de Bourbon by Jean Clouet, Jacques de Brouillard by François Clouet.
- Untitled, mid-16th century.; Print 21 (Box 2)
  Trio of portraits of French court members by School of Clouet. Jeanne III d'Albret, reine de Navarre, princesse de Béarn, comtesse de Foix by François Clouet, unidentified female, Claude de Lorraine Ier, duc de Guise, comte d'Aumale, marquis de Mayenne et d'Elbeuf by François Clouet
- Untitled, mid-16th century.; Print 22 (Box 2)
  Trio of portraits of French court members by School of Clouet. Includes Henri II, King of France by François Clouet.
- Untitled, ca. 17th century.; Print 23-24 (Box 2)
  A sampling of 6 ornamental engravings by Jean Louis Bérain.
- Untitled, ca. late 16th century.; Print 25 (Box 2)
  8 ornamental engravings by Daniel Mignot.
- Untitled, ca. 17th century.; Print 26 (Box 2)
  A set of 8 landscape prints by Willem Buytewech.
- Untitled landscapes and Dance of Death, (ca. 17th century) (1651).; Print 27 (Box 2)
  Two landscapes by Willem Buytewech and 6 images from Dance of Death by Wenceslaus Hollar (engraver) and Abraham van Diepenbeeck (printer).
- Dance of Death, 1651.; Prints 28-29 (Box 2)
  Each print has 8 images by Wenceslaus Hollar (engraver) and Abraham van Diepenbeeck (printer).
- Theatrum Mulierum (Theatre of Women), ca. 1642-1644.; Prints 30-35 (Box 2)
  Each with 18 prints by Wenceslaus Hollar. From Hollar's series on women's style of dress from different countries.
- Sailing Vessels and The Gates of Paradise, (ca. 1560-1565) (ca. 1793).; Prints 36-40 (Box 2)
  Each print has two images from Sailing Vessels series by Pieter Brueghel, the Elder (artist), Frans Huys (engraver). Also five selected images from The Gates of Paradise by William Blake, ca. 1793.